Oowarai Beach
わあ！　ハハハッ…
Touma!
当麻(とうま)～！
当麻！
Tou~ma!
（上条(かみじょう)）
俺は今 学園都市を離れ
インデックスと２人で海に来ている
Right now, I am away from Academy City, spending time at the beach with Index.
もちろん
俺自身が望んだわけではなく
Obviously, this wasn't voluntary on my part.
“とっとと
この町から出ていけ”？
Get out of this city right away?
It seems like the higher-ups are getting cranky about this.
（小萌(こもえ)）
なんか上のほうが
ゴタゴタしてるみたいなんです
At this rate... Kamijyo-chan,
you'll be in a dangerous situation,
このままだと
上条ちゃんの立場も危ういから
ほとぼりが冷めるまでって
一部のお偉いさんたちが
so until the dust settles...
...is what a couple of higher-ups are thinking...
それに 都合してくれた行き先は
えっと…
Oh, and the place you'll be going to is... let's see...
あっ ほら ここ！
なかなか いい所みたいですよ
Ah, here.
Seems like a nice place.
I'm going!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
行く！　私も当麻と一緒に行く！
I'm going with you, Touma!
This will be the first time I go to the beach!
私 海水浴は初めてなんだよ
"No" means no!
ダメったら ダ～メ！
Besides, you're an illegal alien who doesn't even have a valid ID!
大体 お前は ＩＤも発行されてねえ
密入国者状態だろうが
ついてこようったって ゲートで
警備員(アンチスキル)に捕まるのがオチだっつうの
Even if you try to tag along,
I bet you'll get stopped at the city limit!
（警備員）
うん　どうぞ
Go ahead.
How in the world did he just let us go without a second look?!
（上条）
何ですか
その華麗なスルーっぷりは！
...but yeah, just like that,
…と まあ こんな感じで
よく分からないまま
ここにいるわけだが
we ended up here for some odd reason.
And I just get a bad feeling from the name of the place they chose.
Note: "Oowarai" means big laugh/joke/jeer
わざわざ
この海を選んだってとこにも―
そこはかとない悪意を
感じるんだよな
Tou~ma!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）当麻
（上条）うん？
I found a cute hat, and I'm going to give it to you as a present.
かわいい帽子を拾ったから
当麻にプレゼントするんだよ
S-Sure...
お… おう
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
はい　これ
Here you go.
Beware - Large Jellyfish Outbreak - Oowarai Beach
（上条）
痛(いて)え！
Owww!!!
～♪
#15 Angel Fall
Quite a misfortune you experienced so soon after your arrival...
（女将(おかみ)）
ご到着早々
災難でしたね
This year's jellyfish season came quite early though.
（女将）
クラゲの季節には
早いんですけど
（女将）今年はね
（上条）いてっ！
And thanks to that, we have no guests.
おかげで ウチも客足がパッタリで
I'm sorry, Touma.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
ごめんね 当麻
私 本当にクラゲを見るのは
初めてだったんだよ
It was really the first time I've seen a jellyfish.
それじゃ
あとで救急箱 取りに来ますんで
Well then.
I will come back to retrieve the first-aid kit later.
（上条）あっ はい　どうも
（ノック）
Ah, th-thank you.
Excuse me.
（番頭）
失礼します
We just got a call from your party-
（番頭）
先ほど お連れさまから お電話が…
-that they'd be arriving late.
ご到着が遅れるそうで
あしたの朝になると
That they'll arrive tomorrow morning-
え～っ？
もうすぐ会えると思ってたのに！
And I thought we were going to see them soon!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）当麻の…
（上条）分かりました
Touma's-
Okay.
ありがとうございます
Thanks for the message.
Excuse me.
（番頭）失礼します
（せきこみ）
Excuse me.
（女将）
失礼します
ああ！　ガッカリだよ！　ンンッ！
I'm so disappointed!
そう
ここで俺は会うことになっていた
Yes, I was supposed to meet them here.
上条刀夜(とうや)と上条詩菜(しいな)
Kamijyo Touya and Kamijyo Shiina.
つまり 俺の両親に
My parents, that is.
Touma.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
当麻！
Let's go take a bath.
お風呂 行こう
Since I don't see them that often, Komoe-sensei seems to be taking care of me more than normal.
ふだん会えない分
小萌先生が気を回してくれたらしい
And it seems a cousin I grew up with is coming, too.
幼なじみの いとこも一緒だそうだ
Hey Touma.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）ねえ 当麻
（上条）うん？
Yeah?
What kind of people are your parents?
当麻の両親って どんな人？
（上条）
ど… どんなって…
What kind? Umm...
私 楽しみなんだよ
当麻のお父さんとお母さんに会うの
I'm really looking forward to seeing your parents.
ねえ　当麻 聞いてるの？
Hey, Touma, are you listening?!
（上条）
聞いてるよ
あしたになれば分かるだろう
I am.
You'll find out tomorrow, won't you?
ンンッ… あっ！
また そんな意地悪な言い方して！
You're being a meanie again!
教えてくれたっていいじゃない！
How much could it hurt to tell me now?!
大体 当麻は
いつもいつも 私に対して―
And you're always, always so cold, so cruel, so blunt,
冷たくて つれなくて すげなくて
ぞんざいで
ぶっきらぼうで 無頓着で
so rude, so brusque, so indifferent,
にべもなくて…
so unregretful, so hard to grasp-
（上条）
そう　あしたになれば分かる
Yeah, I'll find out tomorrow.
記憶喪失の俺には
当然ながら 両親の記憶がない
I lost my memories, so I obviously don't remember how my parents are,
どんな人たちで
俺は どんな息子だったのか
what kind of people they were, or what kind of son I was.
Will I be able to act naturally before them?
自然に振る舞うことができるのか
（女性）
イエ～…
（MC）
いま人気絶頂の一一 一(ひとつい はじめ)さんです
The red-hot Hitotsui Hajime-san!
（テレビ:観客たち）
キャーッ！　ハジメくーん！
Good evening!
（一）
こんばんは～！
As such, I'm uncharacteristically nervous right now.
（上条）
そんなこんなで―
実のところ 俺はガラにもなく
落ち着かない気分なのだった
つうか
記憶喪失だってバレねえかな
Heck, will they find out I lost my memories?
Well, there's no point worrying about it.
まあ 心配してもしょうがねえか
The fun will start tomorrow.
全ては あしたのお楽しみってな
Yeah?
（上条）
はい…
（電話:番頭）
ゴホッ ゴホッ…
お目覚めでございましょうか？
Are you awake, sir?
Your party just called now-
たった今
お連れさまから電話があり…
ゴホッ…
-that they will arrive soon-
もうまもなくで
ご到着になられると
Oh, okay!
あっ… はい
アア… ハァ…
（刀夜）うん？　当麻！
（上条）あっ…
Touma!
You look good.
元気そうだな　変わりないか？
Anything different?
あ… ああ　父さんも
And you, Dad?
That's right, I wanted to hand you something.
そうだ
お前に渡したい物があったんだ
I went to India on my last business trip.
この間 出張でインドに行ってな
これは そのときのお土産で
This is a souvenir, a local deity called something...
何とかっていう
現地の神さまなんだが
（上条）どうも
（刀夜）うん？
Ah, thanks...
どうした？
まるで初対面の人に会うみたいだぞ
What's the matter?
It's as if you're meeting me for the first time.
Eh, ah-
（上条）
えっ？　ああ いや…
Ah, let me get your bag.
ああ　荷物 持つよ
Take Mom's and Otohime-chan's, as well.
（刀夜）
母さんと乙姫(おとひめ)ちゃんのを頼む
I'm sure they'll be here soon.
もう来るころだ
ここで待っていよう
Wait here.
This person is my father.
この人が 俺の父さん
Sorry about our arrival.
（刀夜）
いやぁ　すまなかったな
We were supposed to get here last night.
本当は
昨日のうちに着くはずだったんだが
ほら　引っ越したばかりで
何が どこにあるやら…
You know, we just moved,
so we don't know where things are.
（上条）
引っ越し？
Move?
I told you, remember?
（刀夜）
言ったろう　先月 電話したときに
We went over this on the phone last month.
Ah, yeah.
そっか　俺が生まれた家は
もう拝めねえってわけか
I see.
I won't ever be able to see the home I was born in.
まあ いいけど
Oh, well...
（乙姫）
お兄ちゃん！
Onii~chan!
（上条）うん？
（刀夜）オッ！　来た来た
Oh, there she is.
お兄ちゃん！
Onii~chan!
あれが 俺のいとこの…
That's my cousin-
（乙姫）お兄ちゃん！
（上条）うん？
Onii~chan!
（美琴(みこと)）
お兄ちゃーん！
Ahh, Oniichan! I wanted to see you so badly!
ああ 当麻お兄ちゃん
会いたかったよ
ねえ 当麻お兄ちゃん
あとで海に連れてってよ 海
Hey, Touma-oniichan!
Take me to the sea later! The sea!
C'mon, please?
（乙姫）ねえ いいでしょう？
（上条）アア…
Just hold it!
ちょ… ちょっと待て こら！
（美琴）
うん？　なに お兄ちゃん？
What, Oniichan?
“なに”じゃねえだろう
なんで お前が ここにいる？
Not "what"!
What are you doing here?!
しかも 何だ？
その気色の悪い妹キャラは
And what's with your disgusting sister acting?
Sister or Sister-in-Law - That is the issue, eh?
（乙姫）何よ！
（上条）父さん…
What~
Dad!
こんなヤツ連れてきて
一体 どういうつもりだ？
Why did you bring someone like her here?!
つうか いつの間に知り合った？
Heck, since when did you know her?
What do you mean "someone like"?
“こんなヤツ”とは なんだ
知り合うもなにも―
What do you mean "since when did I know her"?
この子は お前のいとこの
乙姫ちゃんじゃないか
She's your cousin, Otohime-chan.
ウワッ！　バ… バカ　お前 やめろ
No, yo, cut it out!
それはマズイ　背中… 背中に…
That's bad.
My back-
They're touching my back-
My, my.
Touma-san, is being hugged by Otohime-chan embarrassing because you haven't experienced it in some time?
当麻さん的には
久しぶりに会った乙姫ちゃんに―
抱きつかれるのが
恥ずかしいのかしら？
What the hell do you think you're doing here?
（上条）
てめえ ここで何してる？
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
あらあら！　当麻さん的には…
My, my.
Touma-san, is-
Weren't you sleeping like a pig in the room just now?!
さっきまで
部屋でグースカ寝てただろうが！
いきなり着替えてテレポートって
てめえは白井黒子(しらい くろこ)ですか？
Changing your clothing and teleporting, who are you, Shirai Kuroko?
つうか 何だ？
And! What's with your obvious madam-like, señora-like way of speech?!
そのミセスで マダムで
セニョーラな口の利き方は
（刀夜）こら 当麻
（上条）あっ…
Watch your mouth, Touma.
お前こそ 何だ？
What's with you?
母さんに向かって
その口の利き方は
Talking like that to your mother.
（上条）えっ？
（刀夜）母さんに向かって―
I said, what's with you talking that rudely to your mother.
その口の利き方は何だと言っている
Dad, are you saying...
父さん　あんたは これが―
このＲ－15な映画館から
つまみ出されそうな女の子が―
...that this girl, who looks like she'd get kicked out of a R-15 movie...
...is my mother?
俺の母さんだと？
My, my.
あらあら　当麻さん的には
母さん 年より若く見えるのかしら
Touma-san, are you saying your mom appears younger than her age?
…で こいつが
And that this electrifying shocker of a girl...
この電撃ビリビリ女が
俺のいとこだと？
...is my cousin?
ビリビリって何よ？
What do you mean, shocker?
いかにも
母さんと乙姫ちゃんじゃないか
They are your mother and Otohime-chan, without a doubt.
一体
どうしたっていうんだ 当麻
What's wrong with you, Touma?
What's wrong? EVERYTHING!!!
どうしたも こうしたもあるか！
What is this surprise?
こいつは何のドッキリだ？
“作戦成功”のパネルは どこだ？
Where's the "You've been punked" sign?!
Playing around with the tender soul of a young man like this!
寄ってたかって
いたいけな少年の心を弄びやがって
What kind of grudge do you guys have against me?!
てめえら 俺に
何の恨みがあるってんだ こら！
ま… 待て　落ち着け 当麻
W-Wait, calm down, Touma.
See, look at this.
ほら　これを見ろ
The swimsuit girl drawn on this pen.
このペンに書かれた水着の女性が
ひっくり返すと…
Flip it and-
（ペンの折れる音）
（上条）じゃあな！
Good-bye!
（刀夜）
ま… 待て 当麻
話半ばで どこに行く？
W-Wait, Touma!
Where are you going in the middle of our conversation?
（美琴）待ってよ お兄ちゃん！
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）当麻さん？
Wait, Oniichan!
Touma-san?
ふざけやがって
Toying with me like this...
I never thought my dad would be like that.
あんなトンデモ親父(おやじ)だとは
思わなかったぜ
Welcome...
（御坂(みさか)妹）
いらっしゃいませ
（御坂妹）
お待ちしておりました
We have been waiting for you.
Please... come in...
さあ お上がりください
（息を吹く音）
（刀夜）
あっ お世話になります
Please take care of us.
うん？　どうした 当麻？
What's wrong, Touma?
Y-You're part of this, too, Misaka sister?
（上条）
て… てめえもグルか 御坂妹
Since when were you hiding here?!
一体 いつから隠れてやがった！
...huh?
Ah, please don't mind him.
（刀夜）
ああ　どうか気にしないでください
He's a bit emotional since we haven't seen each other in a while.
久しぶりに会って
感情が高ぶっているだけですから
Thank you for staying here at our resort.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
ようこそ お越しくださいました
I will take you to your rooms.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
お部屋に ご案内いたします
Come, come. This way.
さあさあ　こちらへ どうぞ
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
おや
お連れさまがお目覚めのようで
Oh, your friend is awake now it seems.
Ah, good morning, Touma.
（青髪ﾋﾟｱｽ）
あっ！　おはよう 当麻
Let's go eat breakfast already.
早く 朝ご飯 食べに行こう
AHHHHHHHHHHHHH---
わあ！
Onii~chan!
お兄ちゃーん！
お兄ちゃん！
（美琴）
ハハハッ… 冷たい！
Right now,
俺は今 スクール水着で 妹キャラと
化した御坂美琴と海にいる
I am at the beach with a Misaka Mikoto that's wearing a school swimsuit and pretending to be a sister character.
Obviously, this wasn't voluntary on my part.
もちろん
俺自身が望んだわけではなく
What the hell?!
オンドリャー！
PLACEHOLDER
I can't breathe!
（青髪ﾋﾟｱｽ）
苦しい！　やめてよ 当麻！
You're going to play a part in this, too?!
（刀夜）待て　落ち着け 当麻
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）お客さま お気を確かに
Wait, calm down, Touma!
Sir, please calm down.
In times like these, just take a dip and cool your head, Oniichan.
（美琴）
こんなときは ひと泳ぎして―
頭を冷やしたほうがいいよ
お兄ちゃん
（刀夜）
私たちも あとから行くから なっ？
We'll come over afterwards, okay?
Such misfortune...
不幸だ…
But how long is this comedy act going to last?
…にしても
この茶番 一体 いつまで続くんだ？
もはや
ドッキリってレベルじゃねえぞ
It's no longer at the level of
"You've been punked!" anymore.
Cooled your head a bit now, Touma?
（刀夜）落ち着いたか？ 当麻
（上条）うん？
何を思い悩んでいるのか知らんが
I don't know what you're worrying about, but...
Here, I'll give you this.
ほら これをやろう　出張で
ロシアに行ったときのお土産だ
It's a souvenir I got on my business trip to Russia.
ほら
See?
ほら　ほら
Fun, isn't it?
（刀夜）なっ？　面白いだろう？
（上条）面白くも何ともないわ
No, not at all.
My, my.
ウワッ！
Touma-san, Dad's taste doesn't work on you, huh?
当麻さん的には お父さんの
センスが通じないのかしら
（上条）
お… お前　そ… それ
Y-Y-You... that-
（刀夜）
やあ 母さん
なかなか似合うじゃないか
Mom!
That looks perfect on you.
父さんも奮発した甲斐(かい)があった
It was a great idea for me to have gotten you that.
You were the one who bought this swimsuit?!
この水着
てめえが買ったのか？
これも
てめえのセンスか？
Is this your taste, as well?!
うん
出張で世界を回っていると―
Yeah.
If you go around the world on business trips,
日本の女性は
いささか 洗練さに欠けるというか
you start to see that Japanese women need to be refined a bit-
What are you doing to me so suddenly, Touma?
いきなり 何をする 当麻！
今こそ 俺は確信した
俺の親父はダメな人だと
I am certain now...
...that my father is a failure of a person...
ただの
ロリコンの変態野郎だったと！
...that he is just a damn lolicon pervert!
（青髪ﾋﾟｱｽ）
フフフン フフフン♪
フフフン♪
ハァ… うん？
Oh, there she comes.
オッ！　来たぞ　お前のお友達の…
Your friend-
Tou~ma!
当麻！
ウウ… 当麻！
Touma!
Oniichan, what's wrong with you?
（美琴）
お兄ちゃん どうしちゃったの？
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）当麻さん？
（上条）うるせえ！
Touma-san!
Shut up!
Next in the news.
（ﾃﾚﾋﾞ:ｶｴﾙ医師）次のニュースです
（上条）うん？
With the political scandal that has shaken up the White House,
政治スキャンダルに
揺れるホワイトハウスで―
まもなく
大統領による―
the President will be holding a press conference to explain the situation.
釈明記者会見が
行われることに…
What's the doc doing?
何やってんだ？　先生…
（小萌）ワシントンの古森(こもり)です
（上条）ウワッ！
Komori reporting from Washington, D.C.
With the suspicions surrounding the Office this time,
今回の疑惑を巡り
大統領が どのような
立場を取るのか
it will be interesting to see what stance the President takes
and what will be said-
その発言に
全米の注目が…
What are you doing, Sensei?!
何やってんだ 先生！
（御坂妹）
ちょっと 見えないよ
Hey, I can't see, you know?
The President has arrived.
She is showing a calm, nonchalant face.
余裕の笑みを
浮かべています
Yes, we can!
（黒子）
イエス ウィー キャン
な… 何やってんだ 白井黒子
What is Shirai Kuroko doing...
Hold it...
ちょっと待て
いくら何でも これは おかしい
This is way too ridiculous no matter how you look at it.
This is too well planned for a surprise trick.
（上条）
ドッキリにしちゃ
手が込み過ぎてる
Besides, there's no point in crossing the ocean just to do this trick.
つうか 海を渡って―
ここまでやるなんて
ありえねえ
Assuming it's not a prank...
ドッキリじゃねえとしたら…
Thank you!
（力士たち）
よろしくお願いします
Thank you!
（幼稚園児）
それなら 手前の坂をず～っと…
Then, take this hill road in front of you and go straight-
Shana-tan, moe...
（老人）
シャナたん 萌(も)え～！
This person's uber annoying.
（老女）こいつ マジうざっ！
（男性）着拒したほうがよくね？
Drop the loser.
何だ こりゃ？
一体 何が起きてるんだ？
What the...
What exactly is going on here?
Oniichan!
（美琴）お兄ちゃん！
（上条）ウワッ！
Now, now...
おい！
See?
ほら これ
去年のお正月の写真だよ
This was a photo from New Year's last year.
Do you remember me now, Touma-oniichan?
これで私のこと思い出してくれた？
当麻お兄ちゃん
Are you okay?
ねえ 大丈夫？
なんか 今日のお兄ちゃん 変だよ
You're really weird today, Oniichan.
So, what are you saying?
つまり なにか？
ここに写ってる女の子が
俺のいとこの…
The girl in this picture is my cousin-
そう 私！　竜神(たつがみ)乙姫！
Yup, me!
Tatsugami Otohime!
She can't tell that her own appearance is different in this picture?
こいつ 自分の姿が違うことに
気づいてない？
What's going on?
どういうことだ？
It's as if everyone's inside and outside are "inside out".
まるで みんな 中身と外見が
入れ替わったみたいな
And they don't realize it themselves.
しかも 自分たちが
そのことに気づいてない
一体 どうして…
Why...
フッ… 上条当麻は知っている
経験則で知っている
Kamijyo Touma knows.
He knows from experience.
Even if it's not in my memories,
記憶になくとも―
こういう ふざけたコスプレで
現れるヤツは―
he knows that people that show up in these crazy cosplays are usually his acquaintances.
大抵 俺の知り合いだということを
従って
この場合 俺が取るべき態度は…
And thus, in these situations,
the attitude I should take is-
Hey, long time no-
よう！　久しぶり…
-see...
Question no. 1 - Are you the spellcaster?
（ﾐｰｼｬ）問１　術師は あなたか？
（上条）ええっ？
（ﾐｰｼｬ）
問１をもう一度
術師は あなたか？
Asking question no. 1 again.
Are you the spellcaster?
Please wait.
（神裂(かんざき)）
待ってください　その少年だと
決めつけるのは早計です
It is rash to say that this young man is the suspect.
Hmph, glad we made it in time.
（土御門(つちみかど)）
フゥ… 間に合って良かったにゃ
Tsuchimikado!
土御門！
しかも ちゃんと この俺が
土御門元春(もとはる)に見えてるぜよ
And he actually sees me properly as Tsuchimikado Motoharu.
Yes.
But the fact that he can properly recognize you must mean...
しかし 正しく あなたを
認識しているということは やはり
（土御門）
いやいや ねーちん
No, no, sis.
カミやんの体のどこに
そんな痕跡があるにゃ？
Do you see any traces of that on Kami-yan's body at all?
（神裂）
我々同様
難を逃(のが)れた者と見受けます
We must consider him the same as us; that he was able to escape the spell.
I am a magician from the English Purist Church, Necessarius,
私は イギリス清教 必要悪の教会(ネセサリウス)の
魔術師 神裂火織(かおり)
Kanzaki Kaori.
I came here for the same reason as you.
（神裂）
ここへ来た理由は あなたと同じ
ゆがみの中心を見定めたため
To determine the origin of this distortion.
However, it is unreasonable to conclude that this young man is the caster.
しかし その少年を
術師と見なすにはムリがあります
I am a magician from the Russian Orthodox Church, Annihilatus,
ロシア教会 殲滅(せんめつ)白書の魔術師
ミーシャ＝クロイツェフ
Misha Kreuzhev.
Wow, to be able to see a magician of Annihilatus here!
（土御門）
にゃ～！　殲滅白書のメンバーと
こんな所でお目にかかれるとはにゃ
Question no. 1 - What evidence do you have to say that this man isn't the caster?
（ﾐｰｼｬ）
問１
この男が術師でないとする根拠は？
問２　この男でないとするなら
術師は誰か？
Question no. 2 - If not this man, who is the caster?
（上条）
えっ…
話が全然 見えないんですけど
Wait, I can't tell what's going on here!
Heck, what is Tsuchimikado doing here?!
…ていうか
なんで土御門が ここに？
（神裂）
この少年は魔術師ではなく超能力者
This young man is not a magician, but an esper.
And his level is-
しかも そのレベルは…
（上条）
…て お前ら！
Are you guys just going to ignore the fact that I was almost killed?
殺されかかった俺のことは
スルーですか！　無視ですか！
Just gonna ignore me?
ハァ… うっとうしい
How disagreeable.
Your rudeness and vulgar attitude...
無礼にして 品性下劣な その態度
あなたは少しも成長していませんね
It appears you haven't grown at all...
こいつも俺の知り合いか
フッ… カマかけてみるもんだぜ
This person is my acquaintance, as well?
Good thing I played dumb.
At least tell me what's going on here, okay?
せめて
何が起きてんのかくらい―
教えてくれたっていいじゃねえか
ええ？　神裂よ
How about it, Kanzaki?
Very well.
いいでしょう
当事者に状況を把握してもらわねば
先へは進めませんから
It's best to let all concerned members know what's going on,
else we cannot move forward.
Concerned member?
当事者？　俺が？
Me?
Currently, a certain magic spell is spreading around the entire world.
（神裂）
目下 とある魔術が
世界規模で進行中です
The structure and formula of the magic is unknown.
構成 術式も不明
我々は この魔術を便宜上
“御使堕し(エンゼルフォール)”と名付けました
For convenience purposes, we are calling this magic "Angel Fall".
Angel Fall?
御使堕し(エンゼルフォール)？
Do you know of the Tree of Sephiroth?
“セフィロトの樹(き)”という言葉を
知っていますか？
Shall I say it's a graph that ranks the spiritual classes...
（神裂）
神さま 天使 人間などの
魂を表した―
身分階級表とでも
言えばよいでしょうか
...of the Supreme One, angels, and humans.
通常 人間が
天使の位に上ることはできない
Normally, there is no way a human can attain the rank of an angel.
And the other way around certainly is impossible, as well.
当然 その逆もまた ありえません
In other words, all classes are full.
（土御門）
どの位も
満席状態ってことなんだにゃ
However, when an angel falls to the human class-
ところが
その天使が人間の位に落ちてきた
Time out!
（上条）
タイム！　ちょ… ちょっとタイム
Time out for a bit!
Having a hard time understanding, as expected?
（神裂）
案の定 理解が及びませんか？
Ah, but... angels? This is too much.
いや けど…
いくら何でも 天使って…
You should've experienced, firsthand, the effects of this spell, Kami-yan.
この魔術の影響は 既にカミやんも
目の当たりにしたはずだぜ
Effects?
（上条）
影響？
つまり 外見の入れ替わり
このとち狂った世界の現出ぜよ
Basically, the switching of appearances.
The emergence of this messed up world.
From the distortion caused by the fall of an angel,
天使が落っこちてきたはずみで―
人間の世界の見た目と中身が
バラバラに はぐれちまった
the "appearance" and "content" of
the human world has been completely messed up.
And now, the musical chair game is all about first come, first served.
さて
イス取りゲームは早い者(もん)勝ちだ
"Appearance" will quickly take the place of "content".
見た目は我先に
中身に座ろうとする　その結果…
As a result...
じゃ
みんなの外見が入れ替わったのは…
Then, the fact that everyone's appearance is being switched around is...
While we don't know by whom and
for what purpose this magic was cast,
（土御門）
一体 誰が何の目的で こんな魔術を
発動させたかは不明だが
the important thing is the person in the middle of this distortion...
肝心なのは
このゆがみの中心にいるのが
...and that is you, Kami-yan...
カミやん お前だってことぜよ
（神裂）
あなたは 御使堕し(エンゼルフォール)の―
You are the number one suspect in the Angel Fall incident.
第一容疑者なのです
You escaped the effects of the magic,
かろうじて 魔術の影響を逃れ
その進行を止めんとする魔術師から
and from the viewpoint of the magicians who are trying to stop the effects from spreading,
命を狙われる立場にある
you are one who will be targeted.
But even so, it is hard to reason
the true suspect is Kamijyo Touma.
だからといって この上条当麻が
犯人であるとは考えにくい
One, he does not possess any magical knowledge.
（神裂）
一つ　彼に魔術知識はない
Two, we cannot see any trace of the "load"
typically seen on espers who have used magic.
一つ　超能力者が魔術を使った際に
かかる負荷の痕跡が―
彼の体には認められない
Rebuttal no. 1 - This man has not been affected by the magic.
反論１
この男は魔術の影響を受けていない
なんつったって
カミやんの右手には―
But hey, he's got the Imagine Breaker that can nullify any kind of illusion in this world with his right hand.
どんな異能の力をも打ち消す
幻想殺し(イマジンブレイカー)が宿ってるんだからな
Oh, I see.
そっか　それで…
That's why...
うん？　土御門
Tsuchimikado, how do you know that?!
お前 なんで そのことを…
数価　40 ９ 30 ７
Number value: 40, 9, 30, 7.
Sum of 86.
合わせて86
（上条たち）ウワッ！
（ﾐｰｼｬ）照応
Corresponding to "O' water,
become a serpent and strike like a sword"...
水よ
蛇となりて剣のように突き刺せ
正答　この解を
容疑撤回の証明手段として認める
Correct.
I acknowledge this explanation as evidence for clearing him from suspicion.
Young man, I apologize here for pointing
my blade at you for the wrong reason.
少年　誤った解のために
刃(やいば)を向けたことをここに謝罪する
さてと 容疑は晴れても―
Well then.
Even if you no longer have any suspicion on you,
御使堕し(エンゼルフォール)が カミやんを中心に
展開しているのは事実
it is a fact that Angel Fall is centered around you.
術師は
カミやんの近くにいる可能性が高い
There is a high probability that the caster is near Kami-yan.
It is hard to imagine that a single caster is responsible for a spell of this scale.
これほどの魔術を 術師単体で
発動させているとは考えにくい
There must be a ritual location that has a barrier or a magical seal deployed.
恐らく 結界か
魔法陣を使った儀式場があるはず
儀式場を破壊するか
術師そのものを倒すか
We'd need to destroy the ritual location...
...or defeat the caster himself.
There are only two ways to stop an Angel Fall.
御使堕し(エンゼルフォール)を止める手段は
２つに１つぜよ
（上条）待てや こら
（土御門）うん？
Hold it, now.
What are you, Tsuchimikado?!
てめえ 何なんだよ？　土御門
Why are you on this side of the world?
なんで
こっちの世界に来てんだよ？
How do you know about my right hand?
なんで
俺の右手のこと知ってんだよ？
Answer me, Tsuchimikado?
答えろよ 土御門
フッ… いや だから カミやん
C'mon, Kami-yan.
俺も 必要悪の教会(ネセサリウス)の一員ぜよ
I'm also a member of Necessarius.
～♪
Next Episode
Searching for the caster that started Angel Fall,
Tsuchimikado and I headed for Dad's place.
（上条）
御使堕し(エンゼルフォール)を引き起こした―
術者を探して 俺と土御門は
父さんの家に向かった
The horrible finding we made there was...
そこで見た恐るべきものとは？
Next time, "Kamijyo Touya".
When science and magic cross paths,
次回 「父親(かみじょう とうや)」
this epic will begin!
科学と魔術が交差するとき
物語は始まる